你被监视着
You are being watched.
■
・ 翻译  阿好
・ 翻译  敏基
■
・ 翻译  惠子
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
■
・ 翻译  茶炒栗子
・ 翻译  王小麦
一台每时每刻都在监控你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
■
翻  幸田实果子
译  小马子咧
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖行动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror,
■
・ 校对  阿好
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything...
■
压制  灰灰是菇凉
牵涉普通人的暴力罪行
violent crimes involving ordinary people.
阿包  凭陵新月  Sage  阿包  凭陵新月  Sage  阿包  凭陵新月  Sage  阿包  凭陵新月  Sage
■
时间轴
政府认为这些人无关紧要
The government considers these people irrelevant.
我们不
We don't.
受当局追捕  我们只能秘密活动
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
你永远找不到我们
You will never find us.
特效
灰灰
但无论是受害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
总监
阿好
只要你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
if your number's up, we'll find you.
疑犯追踪
第三季 第九集
档案音频
音频拦截
我们知道奎恩和他对卡尔做的事了
We know about Quinn and what he did to Cal.
档案音频
音频拦截
奎恩  阿伦佐
市长办公室主任
状态
法外活动
组织  HR
职位  头目
身份已知
那你也该知道为什么不能让他逍遥在外
Then you know why he can't get away with it.
要把他带去哪儿
Where are we taking him?
下城区的联邦大厦
Fed building downtown.
联调局可能是我们唯一能信任的了
The FBI may be the only ones we can trust.
法官要见你
The judge has been asking to see you.
有问题吗  法官大人
Do we have a problem, your honor?
你觉得谋杀重罪算不算问题呢
Do you consider a felony murder charge a problem?
要是那贱人警察跟她的持枪同伙
Because if that bitch cop and her gun-wielding cohort
把阿伦佐・奎恩送去联调局关押
get Alonzo Quinn into federal custody,
我们全得被控谋杀重罪
that's what we'll all be facing.
不会被控的
No one is gonna be charged.
我们在路上设了层层关卡
We have checkpoints on all the roads.
他们到不了下城区
They'll never make it downtown.
卡特说她有HR的证据
Carter said she had evidence on HR,
照片  录音
pictures, recordings.
她手上有我跟你们合作的录音带
She has me on tape working with you people.
我们安排人搜查她的住处了
We have a team tossing her place.
我们拿回证据前  不会杀她
No one is gonna kill her until we get that evidence.
我们得对好说辞
We need to come up with a story.
你家里有枪吗
Do you have a firearm in the house?
那边抽屉里
In that far drawer.
好吧  什么说辞
Fine, what's the story?
强盗闯进你家  抢劫一空
Robbers broke into your home, they looted the place,
打死了你
and shot you.
这老东西肯定会交待的
Old man would've talked.
他是打准算盘想做污点证人了
He's got state's evidence written all over him.
处理掉
Get rid of this.
给我抓到卡特警官和阿伦佐・奎恩  要活的
Bring me Officer Carter and Alonzo Quinn alive.
奎恩掉一根汗毛
And if Quinn gets so much as a hangnail,
我唯你是问  明白了吗
I will come after you. Do you understand?
那位西装男呢
What about our pal in the suit?
我早就该了结他了
I should've ended him a long time ago.
放话出去  杀无赦
Tell our friends, shoot to kill.
阴影  胜利
Shadow. Victor.
喝彩  时间
Bravo. Time.
十一月  威士忌
November. Whiskey.
飞行  制服
Flight. Uniform.
X光  结束
X-ray. Close.
三角洲  狐步舞
Delta. Foxtrot.
敢轻举妄动  知道后果吗
Know what happens if you try anything?
我相信自己知道答案
I believe I can fill in the blanks.
我们一定会把你送到下城区联邦大厦
We're not stopping until we get you to the Fed building downtown.
所以撑着别死  听到没
So don't die on us, you hear?
你们忘记了  这是我的城市
You keep forgetting, this is my city.
而你们只有两个人
There's just two of you.
我们处于下风不会太久
We won't be outmatched for long.
芬奇派人来了
Finch is sending the cavalry.
偶尔打扫一下  死不了人
Wouldn't kill you to clean up every once in a while.
何必呢  有你当我的女仆嘛
Why? I got you as a maid.
是吗  女仆要工作啦
Oh, yeah? Well, the maid's gotta go to work.
奥尔森太太要
Mrs. Olson is gonna
前来拜访问候喽
drop in and make sure you're okay.
项链不错啊  爸
Nice necklace, dad.
这是钥匙  聪明小子
It's a key, smart guy.
我朋友掌握了坏人的资料
Friend of mine's got some information on some very bad guys,
我要保护好
and I'm keeping it safe.
靠谱儿吗  就指望你
Sure that's a good idea, trusting you with it?
你老子坚强着呢
Turns out your old man's a pretty tough guy.
那些坏人  才不敢惹呢
The bad guys, they don't want no part of this.
何不少操点儿心  闭眼睡你的觉呢
So how 'bout you mind your own business and get some shut-eye?
晚安  小家伙
Good night, buddy.
什么警察居然不用垂直锁定插销
What kind of cop doesn't use a vertical dead bolt?
搞什么鬼  你从哪儿来的
What the hell? Where'd you come from?
无所谓
It doesn't matter.
重要的是我们要去哪儿
It's where we're going that's important.
拿上枪  莱奈尔
Grab your gun, Lionel.
我猜猜  亲善佳丽先生又有麻烦了
Let me guess, Mr. Congeniality's in some kind of trouble.
可以这么说
You could say that.
里瑟和卡特抓住了HR的头儿
Reese and Carter nabbed the head of HR.
需要我们帮忙把他送去联调局关押
They need a little help escorting him into FBI custody.
准备好了吗
You ready?
我不管你是谁  敢再闯进我家
I don't care who you are, you break in my house again,
我要你后悔
you're gonna be sorry.
我已经后悔了
I'm already sorry,
到皇后区这一路上我都得听你唧唧歪歪了
I'm gonna have to listen to your whiny ass all the way into Queens.
我  只有那条狗才喜欢你  知道不
Me? You know the dog's the only one that likes you, right?
所有乘客请注意
Attention, all passengers.
发现无人看管包裹  请即时上报
Please report any bags left unattended.
抱歉把你扯了进来
I'm sorry I got you into this.
你把我们送到曼哈顿
You get us into Manhattan,
我一个人把奎恩带去联邦大厦
I'll take Quinn to the Fed building alone.
你怎么回事  乔丝
What is it about you, Joss,
什么事都想一个人做
makes you want to do everything on your own?
你怎么回事  约翰
What is it about you, John,
什么人都想救  唯独不在乎自己
that makes you want to save everybody else's life but your own?
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese?
失陪下
Excuse me.
我有坏消息
I have some very bad news.
又出了个号码吧
Guessing this is about a number.
其实是好几个
Several, actually.
耗了点时间才发现都是化名
It took me a while to realize that they were all prior aliases
同一个人的化名
for one person.
你  里瑟先生
You, Mr. Reese.
出什么事了
Something wrong?
一切正常
No more than usual.
看一下你的手机
Check your phone.
HR悬赏你的脑袋
HR has put a bounty on your head,
把这张照片分发了出去
and they're distributing this picture.
我的老棋友打来电话知会说
My old chess partner called to inform me
他的手下不会碰
his men will sit this one out.
以利亚多好心啊
That's nice of Elias.
是的  但不幸的是  只有他们不碰
Yes, but unfortunately, they're the only ones.
看来纽约所有罪犯
It appears that every criminal in New York
都想杀了你
is trying to kill you.
想来也不是想套近乎
Don't suppose they're just trying to be friendly.
西装真高级  可以给你陪葬
That's a nice suit. Maybe we'll bury you in it.
真糟糕  我刚洗过啊
Too bad. I just had it cleaned.
有什么可笑的
Something funny?
地铁  黑帮
Subway, thugs.
让我想起我们的第一次见面
Kind of reminds me of the first time we met.
要换乘R线
Gotta transfer to the "R" Train.
在离联邦广场几个街区的地方下车
It'll drop us a couple blocks from Federal Plaza.
请注意
May I have your attention, please?
由于莱克星顿大道站发生了事故
Due to an incident at the Lexington Avenue Station,
所有开往曼哈顿的地铁都暂时停运
all train service has been suspended to Manhattan.
恐怕不是运气问题
Guessing that's not just bad luck.
那群警察朋友可没准备让我们好过
Our friends in blue aren't making it easy for us.
-别停下  -否则呢
- Keep moving. - Or what?
开枪打我吗
You'll shoot me?
我可正有此意
That's exactly what I'll do.
先给你个警告  这你可没给过卡尔
I'm giving you a warning. That's more than you gave Cal.
芬奇  我需要撤退路线
Finch, I need an exit strategy.
-芬奇  你在吗  -在找这个吗
- Finch, you there? - Looking for this?
你们俩还当你们是故事里的英雄吗
You two still believe you're the heroes of this story?
我的人会封锁皇后区往外的所有地铁  火车和公路
My men will have every subway, train, and road from Queens blocked.
只有一个结局  那可绝不是你们奔向夕阳
This ends one way, and it's not with you riding into the sunset.
走吧
Let's go.
你的人在找三个人
Your men are looking for three people.
我们只需要伪装一下
We just need better camouflage.
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese?
能听到吗
Can you hear me?
肖女士  我和里瑟先生失去联系了
Ms. Shaw, I'm afraid I've lost contact with Mr. Reese.
不怕明说  芬奇
At the risk of stating the obvious, Finch,
你可以问机器他的位置
you could just ask the machine for his location.
我不和机器对话
I don't speak to the machine,
机器也不和我对话  肖女士
and the machine doesn't speak to me, Ms. Shaw.
它和她对话
It speaks to her.
虽然我不知道他们在哪儿
I might not know where our friends are,
但是我知道他们要去哪儿
but I certainly know where they're headed.
准确的说是联邦广场26号
26 Federal Plaza, to be exact.
根据他们最后的位置  有两条路
Based on their last location, there are two direct routes
直接通往曼哈顿  长岛铁路
into Manhattan-- the Long Island railroad
以及通向布鲁克林大桥的278洲际公路
and the B.Q.E. to Brooklyn bridge.
HR一定会在这两个点重兵把守
HR will be patrolling both spots heavily.
你是说  要弗斯科和我兵分两路吗
So are you saying Fusco and I need to split up?
是眼镜儿吗
Is that Glasses?
告诉他我这是最后一次给你们使唤了
Tell him this is the last time I chauffeur your ass.
分头击破  你应该不反对吧
Divide and conquer, I assume that's all right with you.
简直迫不及待
I thought you'd never ask.
你的保卫犬有点问题
Something's wrong with your attack dog.
他看来是比我聪明
He appears to be the smart one.
你怎么还醒着
Why are you still awake?
希望不是做噩梦了
Not bad dreams, I hope.
我曾听说过  女人怀孕时
I heard it said once that a pregnant woman
会在梦中看见她未出生的孩子
may see the face of her unborn child in her dreams.
我看到了每一个数位
I saw every digit,
每一行代码
every line of code
在我建造它时
as I created it.
但你修改过了  是吧
But you've changed that, haven't you?
你找到了办法更改DNA  重写代码
You found a way to alter the DNA to rewrite the code.
所以才会让它跟你对话吗
Is that how you get it to speak to you?
你和她的关系  是你想要的
You have the relationship with her that you wanted.
她尊重
She respects that.
我和她的关系更加
My relationship is more...
亲密
intimate.
抱歉我不该问
Sorry I asked.
为什么要问  为什么如此沮丧
Why are you asking? What's gotten you so upset?
那位柔情铁汉有麻烦了吗
Is the big lug in trouble?
他的号码终于出来了吗
Has his number finally come up?
我并不在乎那家伙
I don't really care for the man myself,
但是  他对你非常重要
but he means a great deal to you.
如果你愿意
So if you can see it fit
放我出去这笼子
to set me free from this cage,
我会把他还给你  毫发无伤
I'll return him to you, unharmed.
我怎么能让你走
How could I ever let you go
我几乎可以确信那样
when I know with an almost absolute certainty
肯定会出事
that bad things will happen?
出事总是会出事
Bad things will happen regardless.
问题是
The question is,
你能让你的朋友出事吗
are you gonna let them happen to your friend?
得了  哈罗
Come on, Harry.
别假装约翰是第一个为你卖命的宠物了
Let's not pretend that John is your first helper monkey.
在他之前  你到底还有过多少个呢
Exactly how many guys did you go through before him?
好梦哟
Pleasant dreams.
感谢载我们一程
Thanks for giving us a lift.
别太舒服了  我们很快就到联邦大厦了
Don't get too comfortable, we'll be at the Fed building soon.
彼特森  你居然也爬起来了
Petersen, surprised you dragged your ass out of bed.
听说有机会开枪杀人
I was told there was a chance to shoot people.
没见着西装男真心失望啊
Imagine my disappointment, suit's a no-show.
也许藏起来了
Probably laying low.
估计他一时半会不会露面了
Doubt he's gonna stick his head out again.
那家伙连法官家都敢闯
Our pal stormed a judge's house.
他不是会低调的人
Subtle he ain't.
他是藏起来没错  但肯定是近在眼前
He's hiding, all right, but you can bet it's in plain sight.
■
追踪对关键执行人的威胁
姓名  权海
法外活动
组织  BTK黑帮
职位  头目
姓名  权海
法外活动
组织  BTK黑帮
职位  头目
弗斯科
Fusco?
我没找到我们的朋友
I haven't spotted our friends,
但找他的可不止我一个
but I'm not the only one looking.
是啊  HR也在布鲁克林大桥设了关卡
Yeah, HR's got a checkpoint at the Brooklyn Bridge too.
没见到我们的人
No sign of our people.
希望他们有办法逃过一劫
Hope they find their way out of dodge.
让我们通过
Get us through,
今晚就没你的事了
you can go about your night.
来了辆救护车
Got a bus coming.
过来
Come on.
拦下救护车
Stop that ambulance!
我接手吧
I'll take it from here.
有幸找到我们的朋友了吗
Any luck finding our friends?
你要是指"有幸"帮他们闯过HR的关卡
If you mean by "luck" helping them escape an HR checkpoint
送他们去了曼哈顿  那没错
and bully their way into Manhattan, then yes.
莱奈尔
Lionel?
弗斯科警探  你还好吗
Detective Fusco, are you all right?
游戏结束  莱奈尔
Game over, Lionel.
怎么处置他  老大
What do you want to do with him, boss?
我有点想法
I got a few ideas.
里瑟和卡特冲破了HR设的路障进入了曼哈顿
Reese and Carter broke through HR's roadblock into Manhattan.
他们要去联邦调查局大厦了
They're on their way to the Fed building.
我听到了  多亏弗斯科警探
I heard. Thanks to Detective Fusco.
不幸的是  他运气用尽了
Unfortunately, he wasn't so lucky.
我能找到他  不过可能没用了
I can find him, but it might not matter.
可能现在已经死了
Might be dead by now.
提醒我下次雇个乐观主义者
Remind me to hire an optimist next time.
乐观主义者也分身乏术
Even an optimist can't be two places at once.
那怎么办  芬奇
So what'll it be, Finch?
弗斯科警探现在孤立无援
Detective Fusco is currently without any aid.
里瑟和卡特就只能靠他们自己了
Reese and Carter will have to make do on their own.
去找警探
Locate the detective.
我在哪儿
The hell am I?
没人能听得到你尖叫的地方
Someplace no one will hear you scream,
因为你会叫得很惨
since you'll be doing a lot of that.
见见这位新朋友
Meet your new best friends.
彼特森是吧  漂亮脸蛋儿容易记
Petersen, right? Always remember a pretty face.
这个呢
How about this?
眼熟吗
Look familiar?
你们搜了我的口袋
You emptied my pockets.
里面估计有线头吧
Think there's some lint in there too.
你真幽默  弗斯科
You're a funny guy, Fusco.
肯定常常哄得你前搭档开怀大笑
Must have had your ex-partner in stitches.
你什么时候见过卡特
When's the last time you saw Carter?
不清楚  让我查查日程表吧
I don't know. Let me check my day planner.
我们知道你今晚跟卡特见面了
We know you met with Carter tonight.
她给了你些东西
She handed you something,
就像是这个
looked an awful lot like this.
开什么的
What does it open?
卡特手上有关于我们组织的信息
See, Carter has information on our organization,
她藏起来了
hidden it somewhere.
根据这钥匙的尺寸和形状
From the size and shape of this key,
应该是开保险箱的
I'd say it opens up a safe deposit box.
这是我的柜子钥匙
It's my locker at the "Y."
欢迎去参观我的脏衣服
You're welcome to my dirty jock.
弗斯科  想看看你运气如何吗
Fusco, want to know your fortune?
你将会事业有成
"You will be unusually successful at your career."
我觉得这个不是真的
You know, I don't think that one's true.
未来激动人心
"A thrilling time is in your future."
这个有点靠谱儿
We're getting close now.
找到了
Here we go.
告诉你的朋友们  他们想知道的
"Tell your friends what they want to know,
否则他们就把你活拆了
or they will break you apart limb by limb."
这个比较像话
That's more like it.
怎么样呢  弗斯科
So what's it gonna be, Fusco?
司机附送赠品
Courtesy of the driver.
等他醒来估计会头疼欲裂
He's gonna have one hell of a headache when he wakes up.
我说过抱歉了
I did say I was sorry.
离联邦大厦只有四个街区了
Fed building's just four blocks up.
看来我们来迟了一步
Looks like we're late to our own party.
我们得步行去了
We'll have to go in on foot.
-走吧  -快走
- Let's go. - Come on.
站住
Hold up.
快快快  走
Come on, come on, come on. Move!
怎么着
'sup?
我们得马上离开街面上
We gotta get off the streets now.
进这儿
In here.
芬奇  需要点帮助
Finch, could use a little help here.
里瑟先生  你在哪儿
Mr. Reese, where are you?
别是我的最终归属  但愿吧  下城区陈尸房
Not my final stop, I hope. City morgue, downtown.
来吧  请自便
Go ahead, make yourself at home.
HR把帮派都派上街了
HR has gangs patrolling the street.
能让莱奈尔来接我们吗
Can you send Lionel to pick us up?
恐怕弗斯科警探已经被HR拘押了
I'm afraid Detective Fusco has been apprehended by HR.
可能他们要用他当筹码
Chances are, they're planning to use him for leverage,
或者更糟
or worse.
我已经让肖女士去找他了
I've asked Ms. Shaw to locate him.
他们抓了弗斯科  是不是
They got Fusco, didn't they?
别担心  肖会找到他的
Don't worry, Shaw will find him.
如果她没找到呢
And if she doesn't?
没  没看到那小子
Nope, no sign of our boy.
该死
Damn it.
不
No!
你知道这不是真肉  是吧
You know that's not real meat, right?
搞什么  你是谁
The hell-- who are you?
热心市民  我们的警察
Concerned citizen. Our police force
配备真应该再
should really be filling up on something more...
有料点儿
substantial.
现在
Now...
打电话给你哥们儿西蒙斯
I want you to call your pal Simmons
查出他把弗斯科警探关在了哪儿
and find out where he's keeping Detective Fusco.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
快打
Do it now,
否则我就扔掉这手榴弹的保险栓  一了百了
or I lose the pin to this grenade... permanently.
你不明白
You don't understand.
你可能会杀了我
You might kill me,
但如果我背叛了西蒙斯
but I cross Simmons,
他会杀掉我的妻子
he'll hunt down my wife,
我的妹妹
my sister.
他会杀光我所有的家人
He won't stop until everybody I love is dead.
求你了
Please.
等等  保险栓给我
Wait, I need that pin!
联邦广场
Federal Plaza.
四个街区  而我们只有十五发子弹
Four blocks and only 15 rounds of ammo between us.
谁知道还有多少HR的人藏在暗处
And who knows how many guys HR has hiding in the shadows?
那我们就等到太阳出来
So we wait until sunup.
光天化日他们不太方便朝我们开枪
Less likely they'll risk taking a shot at us in broad daylight.
你们还不明白  是不是
Still haven't learned yet, have you?
你们无处可躲
There's no place you can hide,
无处可
no place my men won't f--
那是什么
What was that?
镇定剂  应该是吧
A sedative... I think.
想好把他放哪儿了吗
Any ideas where to put him?
愿他安息
Let the man rest in peace.
看吧  说过会让你尖叫的
See, I told you we'd have you screaming.
保险箱在哪儿
Where is the safe deposit box?
告诉他吧  完事儿拉倒
Just tell him, get it over with.
你就这点儿能耐吗
That the best you got?
不
No.
你了解我们的  莱奈尔  还能惨得多
You know us, Lionel. It's gonna get so much worse.
你们还能干什么  再读几个幸运饼干
What are you gonna do, read some more fortune cookies?
把我无聊死
Bore me to death?
看  这就是你的问题  弗斯科
See, that's the problem with you, Fusco.
你总是不好好听  就像跟孩子说话似的
You never listen. It's like talking to a child.
你有个孩子  是吧
You have a kid, don't you?
小家伙叫什么名字来着  李
What's the little guy's name? Lee.
我为那孩子遗憾  真的
I feel sorry for that kid, I do.
他基因不好  像你
He's got defective genes, just like you.
你敢碰他  我保证送你下地狱
You touch him, and I'll send you to hell.
这是承诺吗
Is that a promise?
因为我的承诺  我会遵守
Because when I make a promise, I keep it.
保险箱在哪儿  在哪家银行
Where's the safe deposit box? Which bank?
不说我就杀了你和你的孩子
Or I kill you and your kid.
好吧  了结那孩子
You know what? Put the kid out of his misery
省得他变得像他老子
before he turns out like his old man.
好吧  好吧  好吧
Okay, okay, okay!
那银行在霍博肯
Bank's in Hoboken,
杰斐逊大道和第九大道交界处
Jefferson and 9th,
但现在这么晚不会开门了
but it won't be open this time of night.
他们会为我开门
They'll be open for me.
我去要搜查令  你扣押那孩子
Sit on the kid while I get a warrant,
确保他说的是真话
make sure he's telling the truth.
看着弗斯科警探
Keep an eye on Detective Fusco.
有什么发现
What do you got?
我有西装男的消息
I got a line on the man in the suit.
还以为他甩掉我们了  然后我们看到这个
Thought he gave us the slip. Then we saw this.
他藏在市陈尸房的死人堆里
He's holed up with the stiffs in the city morgue.
很好  更省事  集合人马
Good, saves us the trip. Rally the troops.
跑路装备吗
Care package for the road?
十五发子弹  骨锯  解剖刀
15 rounds, bone saw, scalpel,
还有各种工具
and some assorted tools.
你知道我们得先杀了HR  才能验尸吧
You do realize we gotta kill HR before we can autopsy them.
运用得当  这个也颇有杀伤力
Apply the right amount of force, this can do some damage.
[黎巴嫩]真主党操刀
Hezbollah surgeon.
再偏左五厘米
2 more inches to the left,
就会穿透我的腋动脉
would've cut right through my axillary artery.
[伊拉克]费卢杰
Fallujah.
两百多斤的大块头海军陆战队士兵护送我
300-pound gorilla of a marine escorting me.
前一秒  我们还在巡逻
One minute, we're walking on patrol,
下一秒  我听到一声滴答声
and the next, I hear a click.
地雷吗
Land mine?
他直视着我  化为灰烬
Guy looked right into my eyes, then he was dust.
毫无预兆
Never saw it coming.
时辰到了  就到了
When your time is up, it's up.
好悬
That was a close call.
是啊
Yeah.
那是你最悬的一次吗
Was that your closest?
缝了十三针
13 stitches.
对方如何
How'd the other guy fare?
一度生死未卜
Touch and go for a while.
是剖腹产  泰勒是臀位
It was a c-section. Taylor was breech.
医生不确定他能不能撑下去
Doctors weren't sure if he was gonna make it or not,
只能紧急送我去手术
had to rush me into surgery.
那是我人生中最糟的时刻
It was the worst moment of my life,
结果却是最好的
followed by the best.
你呢  约翰  你最悬的一次呢
What about you, John? What was your closest?
知道对方的名字吗
That's got somebody's name on it?
我
Mine.
有段时间我想了结残生
There was a time I thought about saying good-bye.
失去了一个人
Lost someone.
迷失了自己
Lost myself.
发生了什么事  什么阻止你了
What happened? What stopped you?
我在地铁跟几个混混打架
I got in a fight with some punks on a subway.
被警察扣留了
Cop detained me.
把我带去见你
He brought me to you.
你改变了我的想法  乔丝
You changed my mind, Joss.
你改变了我
You changed me.
里瑟先生  我有些令人担忧的消息
Mr. Reese, I have some alarming news.
我一直在监控警用扫描仪
I've been monitoring the police scanners.
有人报告陈尸房有可疑活动
Someone has reported suspicious activity at the morgue.
我建议你们从西南方的紧急出口离开
I suggest you leave by the southwest emergency exit.
看来我们一时半会儿走不掉
Doesn't look like we're gonna be leaving anytime soon.
我们被包围了
We're surrounded.
接下来  他们会封锁这栋楼
Next, they'll lock down the building,
隔离所有的目击者
seal us off from witnesses, everyone.
HR准备进来大开杀戒了
HR's moving in for the kill.
来吧
Here we go.
你们三个  把他们找出来
You three, flush 'em out.
怎么回事
What's going on?
我们接到线报
We got some reports,
一些破坏狂从后门闯入了  先生
some vandals have broken in the back, sir.
线报  谁说的  这里只有我一个
Reports? From who? It's just me.
铐了他
Cuff him.
你们不能这么做
You can't do that.
封住这保安的嘴
Make sure the rent-a-cop keeps his mouth shut,
看住前门
and watch the front.
能挡住他们吗
Think that'll hold 'em?
必须能
It's gonna have to.
分头找  他们肯定在这儿
Spread out. They're here somewhere.
早餐
Breakfast.
才凌晨四点
It's four in the morning.
我可能无法及时回来
I may not be back in time.
我可能根本回不来了
I may not be back at all.
我无法想象你现在的心情
I can't imagine what it must be like for you.
事到如今  不得不放弃你的心血
After all this time, to have to let go of your creation.
机器仍然给我们号码  格罗夫斯女士
The machine is still sending us numbers, Ms. Groves.
我说的不是机器
I wasn't talking about the machine.
约翰
John.
还不迟
It's not too late.
我能帮你阻止将会发生的事
I can help you stop whatever's about to happen.
请让我帮你
Please let me help you.
再见  格罗夫斯女士
Good-bye, Ms. Groves.
我明白
I understand.
希望有一天你能信任我
I hope someday you'll trust me.
节哀顺变  哈罗德
I'm so sorry for your loss, Harold.
查了银行  有好消息和坏消息
Checked out the bank. Good news and bad news.
坏消息是弗斯科撒谎了
Bad news is Fusco lied.
好消息是你可以杀他了
Good news is you get to kill him.
听起来很好玩  那证据呢
Sounds fun. What about the evidence?
我们还有钥匙
We still have the key.
早晚能找到那家银行
Only a matter of time before we find the right bank.
那孩子呢
And the kid?
我会告诉他地址  我发誓
Look, I'll tell him where it's at, I swear.
看来有人终于想开口了啊
Look who finally wants to talk.
你告诉弗斯科  我承诺过  我会遵守
You tell Fusco I made him a promise, and I keep my word.
两个全除掉
Waste 'em both.
他们在搜查房间
They're tossing rooms.
用不了多久就会找到我们
Won't be long until they find us.
去检查储物柜
Check the supply closet.
也许能找到化学品派上用场
Might be some chemicals that'll come in handy.
约翰
John?
约翰  约翰  别这样
John! John! Don't do this!
抱歉  乔丝  我不能失去你
I'm sorry, Joss, but I can't lose you.
他们会杀了你
They'll kill you.
他们会想  我就指望这个
They'll try, I'm counting on it.
听着  我引开他们
Listen, I'm gonna draw them out.
你趁机带奎恩逃走
You make a run for it with Quinn.
你要是出事
Anything happens to you,
我发誓  我会永远恨你
I swear, I'll hate you forever.
你甩不掉我  记得吗
You're stuck with me, remember?
把奎恩绳之以法
You make sure Quinn gets what he deserves.
另一边见
See you on the other side.
找到那孩子了吗
You got the kid?
是  找到了
Yeah, I got him.
他那垃圾老爸撒谎了
His piece-of-garbage dad lied.
你知道该怎么办
You know what to do.
我不在乎你怎么对我  放过我儿子
I don't care what you do to me, just let my kid go.
这样吧  我给你机会告别
Tell you what, I'll let you say your good-byes.
让那孩子接电话
Put the kid on the line.
你下手的时候让弗斯科听着
Let Fusco listen in while you do it.
临终遗言  别浪费了
Last words, make 'em count.
爸
Dad?
李
Lee?
李  没事的
Lee... it's gonna be okay.
我陪着你  好吗  我陪着你
I'm right here with you, okay? I'm right here with you.
闭上眼睛  好吗
Just close your eyes, all right?
我爱你  没事的
I love you. It's gonna be okay.
莱奈尔
Lionel.
没事了
It is gonna be okay.
李没事
Lee is fine,
他们派来杀他的那人才有事
but the guy they sent to kill him isn't doing so good.
想着这些混蛋会冲你儿子来
Figured these scumbags would come after your kid.
谢谢你  谢谢你
Thank you, thank you.
但是  莱奈尔
But, Lionel,
你明白这意味着我无法去救你
you understand this means I can't be there for you.
我不得不选
I had to choose.
想着你会更希望我来这儿
Figured you'd want me to come here instead.
是  你做得对  你做得对
Yeah, you did good. You did good.
抱歉  莱奈尔
I'm sorry, Lionel.
看来你的运气用完了
Looks like your fortune's run out.
向来也没什么运气
Never did have very good luck.
看来米勒警官也一样
Turns out neither did Officer Miller.
我朋友杀了他  我孩子没事了
My friend killed him. My boy is fine.
那改变不了你的命运  我有一整夹子弹
Doesn't change your fate. I got a full Mag.
唯一的问题就是先打哪儿
The only question is where to shoot first?
杀过人吗  彼特森
Ever kill someone, Petersen?
最近没有
Not recently.
要扳倒一群腐败警察  不可能没有伤亡
Can't take down a group of bent cops without having casualties.
总有人免不了一死
Someone was always gonna end up in a casket.
事实上  像你我这样的人
Truth is, guys like you and me,
迟早有一天会中上一枪
we're all gonna catch a bullet sooner or later.
最多只能希望有人握住你的手
Best you can hope for is someone to hold your hand
陪你流尽最后一滴血
while you bleed out.
真贴心
That's sweet.
要我握住你的手吗  弗斯科
You want me to hold your hand, Fusco?
我忘了  我们打断你手指了
I forgot, we broke your fingers.
是啊  你忘了
Yeah, you did.
所以我再断个大拇指也无所谓
Which made it no big deal for me to break my thumb.
有事吗
Can I help you?
西蒙斯警官说你可能需要我的帮忙
Officer Simmons said you might be in need of my assistance.
是吗  你是谁
Yeah? Who are you?
我是在你倒地时会接住你的人
I'm the guy that's gonna catch you when you fall.
抱歉  我不太擅长
Sorry, I'm not very good at this.
他们就在这儿  找到他们
I know they're here. Find 'em!
他在那儿  开枪
There he is! Shoot him!
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch.
快点  快点  跟上我啊  该死
Come on, come on. Follow me, damn it.
芬奇  我没子弹了  也没时间了
Finch, I'm out of bullets and out of time.
确保卡特的安全
Make sure Carter gets to safety.
会的  里瑟先生
Will do, Mr. Reese.
卡特警探  本区安全了
Detective Carter, the area is clear.
你现在可以离开了
You are free now to exit the building.
醒醒  我们要出去了
Wake up. We're checking out.
快点
Come on.
关键执行人状态
威胁
临近威胁
距离
弹药
存活几率
站住别动
Hold it right there!
你有武器吗  先生  你带枪了吗
Do you have a weapon, sir? Are you armed?
里瑟先生  你还好吧
Mr. Reese, are you okay?
是  我还好
Yes, I am.
收到线报说
Got a tip that
有个疑似是你的男子在大秀武器
a man matching your description was brandishing a weapon.
我找到了两名正直的纽约警察
I somehow managed to locate two of NYPD's honest cops.
你有权保持沉默
You have the right to remain silent.
你说的每句话都将成为呈堂证供
Anything you say can be held against you.
明白吗
Do you understand?
我猜你宁进监狱  也不愿送命
I assumed you'd prefer incarceration to death.
确实  谢了
I do, and thanks.
你永远别想给我定罪  这是我的城市
You'll never get a conviction, not in my city.
这曾经是你的城市  现在不是了
This used to be your city. Not anymore.
我是卡特警官  这是阿伦佐・奎恩
Officer Carter. This is Alonzo Quinn.
特大消息今晨震撼纽约警界
New York City's police department has been rocked this morning
犯罪组织
被消除
阿伦佐・奎恩被捕
with the arrest of Alonzo Quinn.
阿伦佐・奎恩涉嫌
Alonzo Quinn has been booked
担任HR头目
on suspicion of being the ringleader of HR.
警方仍在寻找派崔克・西蒙斯警官
Police are still searching for Officer Patrick Simmons,
奎恩  阿伦佐
市长办公室主任
关押中  身份已知
西蒙斯  派崔克
警员
位置不明
此人据传是奎恩的副手
who they believe is Quinn's second-in-command.
恭喜  警探
Congratulations, Detective.
复职为警探了  是吧
It is Detective again, isn't it?
我可不想念那身制服
Can't say I miss the uniform.
似乎约翰・都[无名氏]被关在第三分局了
It seems John Doe is being held at the third precinct.
我的律师们正在努力救他
My lawyers are trying to extricate him.
希望约翰能多忍段时间  少找点儿麻烦
Let's just hope John can stay out of trouble for a long while.
还是说你的电脑另有打算
Or has your computer told you otherwise?
你说什么
What did you say?
否则你怎么可能知道
How else could you know
有人就要遭遇不测
when someone's about to be in trouble?
我想着你造了某种超级电脑
I just figured you built some sort of supercomputer
能吸取并过滤政府情报
that can siphon information from government feeds.
厉害
I'm impressed.
我是警探啊
I am a detective.
说到这个  要工作了
Speaking of which, duty calls.
我会去趟三局
I'll drop by the third,
确保我们那位朋友被释放
make sure our friend gets released.
非常感谢  乔丝
I'd appreciate that, Joss.
你不该在工作吗
Shouldn't you be at work?
我也很高兴和你聊天
Nice to talk to you too.
马上就来  帮我占个座
I'll be in later. Keep my seat warm.
还有  你回来真好  搭档
And, nice to have you back, partner.
回来真好  等会见
Glad to be back. I'll see you soon.
真像他老爸  看来他没事了
Chip off the old block, huh? Looks like he's doing okay.
而你嘛  看上去烂透了
You, on the other hand, look like crap.
听说你中过弹
Heard you took a bullet.
是啊  那蠢材打在我肉多的地方了
Yeah, stupid bastard shot me where I had plenty of padding.
要是我就一枪爆头
Would've gone for the head shot myself.
当然了  你那儿肉也挺多
Of course, you got plenty of padding there too.
得得得
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
谢谢你  真的
Thank you, truly.
闭嘴  开车  莱奈尔
Shut up and drive, Lionel.
我是卡特  你没说你的名字
I'm Carter. You didn't give us a name.
只有在你有麻烦的时候
Seems like the only time you need a name now
别人才会问起你的名字
is when you're in trouble.
这么说  我是有麻烦了吗
So am I in trouble?
把他们送进了监狱  卡特
Got your man locked up, Carter.
感觉不错吧
Must feel good.
没抓到全部
Not all of them.
还是没找到那位西蒙斯
Still haven't been able to locate our pal Simmons.
他藏不了一辈子  我们会抓住他
Can't hide forever. We'll get him.
好了  我的武器呢
All right, where's my weapon?
约翰・都没有持枪许可
John Doe didn't have a permit.
你的枪已经属于纽约警局了
Your gun's property of the NYPD now.
也是该买点新货了
Time I got some new hardware.
有人来接你了
Looks like your ride is here.
我们都很担心你
Guess we were all worried about you.
如果我真的命数将尽
If my number was up,
很高兴你在我身边
I'm just glad I was with you.
陪我度过生命的终点
No one I'd rather be with at the end.
时辰到了
Your time's up.
说过我会了结你
Told you I'd end you.
不  别想
No, not today!
乔丝  乔丝  我在
Joss, Joss, I'm here.
没事的
It's okay.
我得  我得见我儿子
I need-- I need to see my boy.
我得告诉他
I need to tell him--
你会的  你会的
And you will, and you will.
撑住
Just stay with me.
答应我  你会照看他
P-promise me you'll look in on him.
我不用  你不会有事的  知道吗
I won't have to 'cause you're gonna make it, okay?
答应我你会告诉他
Promise me you'll tell him.
他知道  乔丝
He knows, Joss.
他知道
He knows.
约翰
John...
别让这
don't let this--
乔丝
Joss--